Guide to the Grand Street Publications, Inc. Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Correspondence, 1981-2000
  - Subseries II.1: Authors, 1981-1990
    Correspondents represented within the general alphabetical folders include Noam Chomsky, Anne Carson, Arthur Danto, Gavin Ewart, Robert Fagles, Seamus Heaney, Christopher Hitchens, Richard Howard, P J Kavanagh, Edward Said and Virgil Thomson. Two letters by Louise Bogan from 1955 are included in "F" folder under Elizabeth Frank; Frank used Bogan's personal letters to a young Sonnenberg as background for a piece she wrote on Bogan in Grand Street.
    - Previously Catalogued Correspondence
      - Annan, Noel Gilroy, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Ashbury, John, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Carruth, Hayden, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Clamitt, Amy, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Cockburn, Claud, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Edel, Leon, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Empson, William, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Ewart, Gavin, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Hamburger, Michael, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Hersey, John, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Hollander, John, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Howe, Irving, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Hughes, Ted, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Kempton, Murray, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Koch, Kenneth, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Laughlin, James, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Merrill, James, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Merwin, William Stanley, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Narayan, Rasipuram Krishnaswamy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Padgett, Ron, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Rama Rau., Santha, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - [Jackson] Riding, Laura, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Steegmuller, Francis,1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Straight, Michael, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Thomson, Virgil, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Trevor, William, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Updike, John, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence
      - A, 1984- 1989, (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Annan, Noel, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Arrowsmith, William, 1983-1986 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - B, 1981-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Bernard, Kenneth, 1982-1986 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Bowerstock, G.W., 1982-1988 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Bromich, David, 1980s (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - C, 1983-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 6 to 7)
        (also includes Anne Carson and Noam Chomsky)
      - Carver, Raymond, 1982-1984 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Christopher, Nicholas, 1981-1984 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - Clampitt, Amy, 1982-1984 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - Clay, Diskin, 1982-1984 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Cockburn, Claud, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - Corn, Alfred, 1982-1985 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - D, 1982-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 14 to 15)
        (also includes Arthur Coleman Danto)
      - E 1981-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 16 to 17)
        (also includes Gavin Ewart)
      - Edel, Leon, 1981-1982 (Box 43, Folder 18)
      - Empson, William, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - Welch, Everman, 1983-1985 (Box 43, Folder 20)
      - F, 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 21 to 22)
        (also includes Robert Fagles)
      - Fainlight, Ruth, 1981-1988 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Feldman, Irving, 1982-1984 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - G, 1983-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Gifford, Henry, 1982-1989 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Green, Peter, 1982-1988 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - H, 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 7 to 8)
        (also includes Seamus Heaney, Christopher Hitchens and Richard Howard)
      - Haas, Diana, 1982-1985 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Hall, Donald, 1982-1984 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Hamburger, Michael, 1982-1985 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Hollander, John, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Howard, Richard, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - I, 1982-1988 (Box 44, Folder 14 to 15)
      - J, 1983-1987 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Jackson Riding, Laura, 1981-1983 (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - Jones, D.A.N., 1984-1988 (Box 44, Folder 18)
      - K, 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 19 to 20)
      - L, 1981-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Langer, Elinor, 1982-1989 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Laughlin, James, 1983-1988 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - M, 1981-1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Merwin, W.S., 1981-1985 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Michie, James, 1981-1982 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Millhauser, Steven, 1982-1984 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Minot, Susan, 1982-1984 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - O-P, 1982-1985 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - R, 1982-1985 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Raine, Craig, 1983-1984 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Ricks, Christopher, 1981-1983 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - S, 1982-1985 (Box 45, Folder 14)
        (also includes Edward Said)
      - Salter, James, 1980s (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Salkey, Andrew, 1982 (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - Steegmuller, Francis, 1982-1985 (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - T, 1983-1984 (Box 45, Folder 18)
        (also includes Virgil Thomson)
      - [Wade, Sidney], 1985 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Subseries II.2: Agents and Publishers, 1981- 2000
    The majority of materials from this subseries originate from the second half of Grand Street's existence from the 1990s onwards. Correspondence from agents is organized alphabetically by agency rather than by agent. Materials from agents and publishers include negotiations of rights and contracts and submission and rejection letters.
    - Agents
      - General, 1981- 1985 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - General, 1993-1999 (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - A-C, 1994-1999 (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - D-F, 1994-1999 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - G-H, 1994-1999 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - German Agents, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - I-N, 1994-1997 (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - O-R, 1995-1998 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - S-U, 1994-1999 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - W-Z, 1994-1998 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Publishers
      - General, 1993- 2000 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - General, 1989-1990, (5 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 45 to 49)
      - Berlin Issue Correspondence, 1999 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - Columbia University Press, 1994- 1997 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Crown Publishing Group, 1993-1997 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Doubleday, 1993-2000 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1994- 1999 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Foreign Publishers, 1993-1998 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - German Publishers, 1992-1994 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Grove Atlantic, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Harcourt Brace, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Harper Collins, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Henry Holt and Company, 1993-2000 (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Houghton Mifflin, 1996-1999 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Hyperion, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Knopf, 1993-2000 (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - Kodansha Press, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - Little Brown, 1995-1999 (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Macmillan, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - Morrow, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - New Directions, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 18)
      - The New Press, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 19)
      - Norton, 1995-1999 (Box 47, Folder 20)
      - Pantheon, 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 21)
      - Penguin U.S.A., 1993-1999 (Box 47, Folder 22)
      - Random House, 1993-1996 (Box 47, Folder 23)
      - St Martin’s Press, 1993-1996 (Box 47, Folder 24)
      - Simon and Schuster, 1994-1999 (Box 47, Folder 25)
      - Sokmen, Muge Gursoy, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - Verso, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 27)
- Series III: Production, 1990-2004
  Production and administrative files from the 1990s on are contained within this large subseries, which is arranged alphabetically by subject. Materials relating to the printing and distribution of Grand Street, financial files, contracts from authors, promotional materials and press clippings, and reports from international bookfairs are included within this series. The files relating to Grand Street's website changeover offer a glimpse into the postmillennial relationship between print and online journalism. These detail Grand Street's unsuccessful reinvention as an online only magazine in 2000 and its attempted shift back to print in 2003. Also here are research files about other literary webzines, authors contacted for the online "dispatches column and internal correspondence about the changeovers. An index of authors and works featured in Grand Street is also included in this subseries.
  - Bookfairs, 2000-2003, (3 Folders) (Box 75, Folder 38 to 40)
  - Contracts and Publishing Agreements, 1993- 2003, (36 Folders) (Box 76, Folder 1 to 36)
  - Design, 1996-2003, (4 Folders) (Box 76, Folder 37 to 40)
  - Distribution, 1991-2000, (9 Folders) (Box 76, Folder 41 to 50)
  - Distribution, 1991-2000, (4 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Editorial and Print History, 1992-2004, (29 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 5 to 34)
  - Financial, 1994-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 35 to 36)
  - Human Resources, 1993-2003, (8 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 37 to 44)
  - Index, 1981-2001, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 50 to 51)
  - ISBN Logbook, 2004 (Box 77, Folder 52)
  - Press and Publicity, 1993-2003, (4 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 52 to 55)
  - Press and Publicity, 1990-1996 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Printing, 1994-1999 (Box 78, Folder 2 to 6)
  - Website Changeover, 1999-2004, (36 Folders) (Box 78, Folder 7 to 43)